Joomart Achekeev

 $joomart.achekeev @gmail.com \mid (609)\ 455-3245 \mid Plainsboro, New\ Jersey \mid linkedin.com/in/joomart-achekeev/\mid github.com/jomadata \mid jomadata.github.io$

Skills

Data mining, Data Cleaning, Data Processing, Data Engineering, Python, General programming, Functional programming, Object oriented programming, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, NLTK, Tensorflow/Keras, Django Templates, Django Rest API, PostgreSQL, Docker, Linux, MS Excel, MS Power Point, Prezi, MS Office, Tableau, others

Profile

Inquisitive and result-oriented Data Scientist, with 5+ years of experience in backend web development and an international certification in project management. My approach is based on breaking down the problem into small, easily solvable, parts and tackling them one by one. I seek to continuously develop my skills, expand my knowledge and embrace the world as my data.

Experience

Online Data Science Immersive Fellow, Oct 2021 – Jan 2022

General Assembly, New York, United States

Completed 3 individual and 2 team projects with use of various machine learning models: <u>Linear regression model</u>, <u>Web scraped data and tuned NLP classification model</u>, <u>Decision Tree models</u> (AdaBoostClassifier, DecisionTreeClassifier, ExtraTreesClassifier), <u>Stacked linear regression and neural network model</u>, <u>NLP extraction of additional review dimensions</u>

Backend web developer, Sep 2017 – Jul 2021

Yorc, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

- Developed backend support for web applications including design and configuration of databases
- Close cooperation with clients on meeting their needs/demands
- Collaboration with UX/UI, Frontend teams to ensure proper frontend-backend integration
- Troubleshooting and review of own, legacy and colleagues' projects
- Used tech stack: Python 3, Django Rest API, PostgreSQL, Docker, Pandas, Numpy
- Projects developed for banks, trade companies, international organizations (USAID, DPI)

Junior Backend web developer, Aug 2016 – Aug 2017

Put In Byte, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

- Design and configuration of databases and backend applications
- · Developed, tested and debugged programs for internal and client use
- Trained in reviewing Python code for troubleshooting and debugging
- · Unit testing of own and colleagues' codes
- Used tech stack: Python 3, Django Templates, PostgreSQL, Docker
- Projects developed for travel agencies, media companies, international organizations (UNICEF)

Backend web development intern, Apr 2016 – Jul 2016

Put In Byte, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

- Designed robust, scalable, secure, and globalized web-based applications to ensure the continuity of all business processes and client satisfaction.
- Backend framework design in Django Templates, Django Rest API basics
- Collaboration with frontend developers to ensure proper frontend-backend integration
- Multiprocessing web scrapper development (BeautifulSoup)

Research Project Manager, Nov 2013 - Mar 2016

M-Vector Research and Consulting, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

- Managing several analytical research projects (social and marketing) at a time
- · Cooperation with field data gathering team
- Full research project management from initial problem identification to final research reporting (narrative, analytical and financial)
- Review and submission of the final version of research report

Research Analyst, Feb 2011 - Oct 2013

M-Vector Research and Consulting, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

- · Development of data collection methods and instruments
- · Data processing, analysis and cleaning
- Overview of other available research in the field or of similar topic.
- · Develop narrative, analytical and financial reports
- Develop visual report components (graphs, general tables)

Education

General Assembly, United States

Data Science Immersive Graduate (Certification)

OSCE Academy, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Master of Arts of Economics (Diploma in Economic Governance and Development)

American University in Central Asia, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Bachelor of Business Administration (Diploma in Marketing and Management)

Certification

Project Management Level-C Certificate from International Project Management Association (#LATV-C0155) - Dec 2020